

Arsslen Idadi

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · NET EXPERT

23, Magon street, Gammarth Village, Tunis, 1057, Rep. of TUNISIA

🛘 (+216) 53 299 093 | 🗷 arsslen.id@gmail.com | 🎁 www.arsslensoft.co | 🖸 Arsslensoft | 🛅 arsslen-idadi

"Leadership is earned rather than taken."

Summary.

Current CTO & Software Engineer in start-up company GOMYCODE Corp. 9+ years experience specializing in .NET Development, architecture/design, backend/infrastructure, web development, computer security and DevOps. A geek who loves creating digital tools that impacts our daily lives. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and continuously learning new technologies and tools.

Experience ____

GOMYCODETunis, Tunisia

CHIEF TECHNOLOGY OFFICER

- Develop technical aspects of the company's strategy to ensure alignment with its business goals.
- Supervise system infrastructure to ensure functionality and efficiency.
- Use stakeholders' feedback to inform necessary improvements and adjustments to technology.
- · Discover and implement new technologies that yield competitive advantage and help departments use technology profitably.
- Monitor KPIs and IT budgets to assess technological performance.
- · Build quality assurance and data protection processes.

GOMYCODE Tunis, Tunisia

SOFTWARE ENGINEER Oct. 2017 - PRESENT

- Determines operational feasibility by evaluating analysis, problem definition, requirements, solution development, and proposed solutions.
- Documents and demonstrates solutions by developing documentation, flowcharts, layouts, diagrams, charts, code comments and clear code.
- Backend development using ASP.NET Core and Node.JS.
- · DevOps (Docker/Kubernetes...) & Administrating linux systems (CentOS, Ubuntu), configuring servers...
- Configuring and setting up the IT infrastructure (Network, hardware, software).
- Frontend development (ES6, React, Redux, Redux Saga).

Phexonite Tunis, Tunisia

CoFounder & Software Developer

Aug. 2016 - Oct. 2017

Apr. 2010, PRESENT

Oct. 2017 - PRESENT

- DevOps & System administration (Linux [CentOS/Debian]).
- Unity3D game development.
- Design, Implement, Test and Publish .NET Desktop and Web applications for clients as a freelancer.

Arsslensoft Tunisia

Founder & Software Developer

- Design, Implement, Test and Publish .NET Desktop and Web applications in various fields (e.g. Virtual Assistant, Antivirus, Compiler construction. IDE. Web Browser).
- PKI & X509 (Extended validation, code signing, class 1-5 certificate generation according to CA Web browser forum guidelines).

Licenses & Certifications

CERTIFICATES

Apr 2017 MTA EXAM 98-361, Software Development Fundamentals

Dec 2018 MTA EXAM 98-383, Introduction to Programming Using HTML and CSS

Tunis, Tunisia

Dec 2018 MTA EXAM 98-382, Introduction to Programming Using JavaScript

Tunis, Tunisia

Tunis, Tunisia

Education

INSAT (National Institute of Applied Science and Technology)

Tunis, Tunisia

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Sep. 2014 - Exp. Jul. 2019

• Graduated with the excellent mention.

Extracurricular Activities

August 3, 2019 Arsslen Idadi · Résumé

TUNIROBOTS INSAT TUNISIA

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING TEAM LEAD Sep. 2016 - Sep. 2018

- Designed and implemented the score application.
- Put in place communication tools and facilitated teams coordination.
- Participated in the preparations of the event day.
- · Led the software engineering team.

Microsoft Club INSAT

Tunisia

TECHNICAL LEAD

Sep. 2016 - Jun. 2017

- · Provided technical guidance for the club members.
- · Trained club members on .NET technology.

Extracurricular Projects

OrigiSign Certification Tool

Available on Github

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT ARSSLENSOFT

Oct. 2016 - Dec. 2016

- Designed and implemented an interactive GUI PKI management tool in (C#) based on BouncyCastle and OpenSsl.
- Custom X509 Extension Visual Programming using ASN.1 Code generation.
- Supports all standard X.509 and ASN.1 fields and extensions.
- Integrates an OCSP server based on CRL files.

Developer Studio Available on Github

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT ARSSLENSOFT

Nov. 2012 - Sep. 2014

- Designed and implemented an integrated development environment in (C#).
- · Supports plugins and languages integration, code completion, projects, single source file, syntax highlighting, refactoring, visual form designer.
- Published and maintained multiple editions (i.e: Pascal Edition, Pawn Edition, Professional Edition, Arsslen Language Edition) and multiple versions until version 3 (2013, 2014, 2015).

Kavprot Smart Security

Available on Github

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT ARSSLENSOFT

Oct. 2011 - Jun. 2012

- Designed and implemented a security suite in (C/C++, C#).
- Integrated Parental control, Firewall, AntiVirus, Malicious web site protection using proxy interception, File Vault, Heuristics analysis features.
- Gathered a viral database of 4 Million signatures (ClamAV and other sources).

Fireweb Navigator Available on Github

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT ARSSLENSOFT

Sep. 2010 - Aug. 2013

- Designed and implemented a GeckoFx based web browser application in (C#).
- Integrated smart search features with a Virtual Assistant.
- Published and maintained the software until version 9.

VATU Compiler Available on Github

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER AT ARSSLENSOFT

Dec. 2015 - Feb. 2016

- Designed and implemented the BNF language grammar.
- Designed and implemented all the necessary components required to construct the compiler (i.e: Lexer, Parser, Semantic Analyzer, Flow Control, Optimizer, Code generator, Linker) in (C#).
- Implemented a mini kernel based on Vatu language and assembly.
- Introduced revolutionary features (e.g.: Custom operator symbol definition, Interruption functions, Custom system call conventions).

August 3, 2019 Arsslen Idadi · Résumé